Max Bohm
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Max Bohm papers
1873-1970, bulk 1880-1959
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Bohm, Max
5.4 linear feet
The papers of painter Max Bohm measure 5.4 linear feet and date from 1873-1970, with the bulk of the material dating from 1880-1959. Biographical material includes a file concerning the Provincetown artist's club The Beachcombers. Also found is detailed family correspondence, as well as general correspondence that includes exchanges with patron Mary Bucher Longyear and dealer William Macbeth. The papers contain scattered business records; five diaries written by Bohm's wife Zella; other notes and writings; art work including fifteen sketchbooks, loose drawings, and oil paintings; printed material; and photographs of Bohm, his family, and colleagues including artists attending a Salmagundi dinner. There is also a motion picture film Six Foot Art, in Which Max Bohm, Member of the National Academy Tells How He Does It.
Provenance
The Max Bohm papers were donated in two installments in 1972 by Esther Locke and Elizabeth Schwarz, the artist's daughters.
Separated Material
Biographical material, scattered letters, notes and writings, drawings, clippings, exhibition catalogs, booklets, a scrapbook, and photographs of Bohm, his family, colleagues, and residences were loaned for microfilming in 1972 and returned to the donor. Loaned materials are available on microfilm reels 420-421 and for interlibrary loan, but are not described in the container listing of this finding aid.
Restrictions on Access
Use of original papers requires an appointment.
Biographical Note
Max Bohm was born on January 21, 1868, in Cleveland, Ohio, the son of Henry and Emilie Bohm.
Bohm began his study of art in 1887 when he accompanied his aunt, Anna Stuhr, on the first of several voyages to France. He studied in artist communities in Brittany and in Paris at the Académie Julian with Boulanger, Lefebvre, and Benjamin Constant. He also traveled to Belgium, The Netherlands, and Germany.
In 1895, Bohm attended an open school of painting in Etaples on the coast of France, and during the winter months he taught painting at a school in London, England. His painting En Mer was awarded the Gold Medal by the Paris Salon of 1897.
While teaching in Etaples in 1898, Bohm married one of his pupils, Zella Newcomb, an art teacher from Carlton College in Minnesota. In 1900, the Bohms traveled to Italy for several months before returning to Minneapolis, Minnesota, where Bohm established a studio. After trying to find affordable studio and living space in New York City, Bohm moved his family back to France in 1902. Bohm established a studio in Paris for two years and during the summer months his wife and children moved to the less expensive and cooler coastal towns of France. Bohm continued to display his work in the annual Paris Salons.
From 1905 until the summer of 1908, the Bohm family lived primarily in England. In 1909, Bohm entered and won the Cleveland Court House mural competition, prompting the family to return to the United States for several months. They returned to Paris the following year, where Bohm established a studio and worked on the Cleveland Court House mural. Again, Bohm's wife and children would live in French coastal towns, while Bohm was on extended visits to Paris, London, or the United States.
Sometime around 1911, Bohm became acquainted with Mrs. Mary Bucher Longyear, a wealthy follower of Mary Baker Eddy and Christian Science. Over the next decade, Mrs. Longyear commissioned many works by Bohm and supported his career. In May of 1912 Bohm's mural, First New England Town Meeting, was installed in the new Cleveland Court House and arrangements were made with Macbeth Galleries to exhibit Bohm's work. Late in 1913, Bohm became involved with the Pan-Pacific International Exposition where his painting Promenade won the Gold Medal in 1915.
During World War I, the Bohm family fled France and temporarily settled in Tuckahoe, New York, and Bohm made frequent visits to his patron, Mrs. Longyear, in Boston. In 1916, the Knoedler Gallery exhibited Bohm's murals for Mrs. Longyear's music room. Also during this time, the family enjoyed spending summers in Provincetown, where Bohm joined The Beachcombers, an organization of artists.
In 1919, the Bohms built a house in Bronxville, New York, for easy access to New York City, while simultaneously purchasing a cottage in Provincetown. While the house was being constructed, Zella and the children became boarders in the home of painter Spencer Nichols, who also lived in Bronxville. During this year, Max Bohm, Jr., entered Harvard University while Mrs. Longyear continued to provide commissions for Max Bohm's art work.
Between 1922 and 1923, Bohm had exhibitions in Greenwich, Connecticut, Washington, D.C., and at the Grand Central Galleries, with his painting En Mer being exhibited at the National Academy of Design.
Max Bohm died on September 19, 1923 in Provincetown, Massachusetts.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of painter Max Bohm measure 5.4 linear feet and date from 1873-1970, with the bulk of the material dating from 1880-1959. Biographical material includes a file concerning the Provincetown artist's club The Beachcombers. Also found within the papers is detailed family correspondence, as well as general correspondence that includes exchanges with patron Mary Bucher Longyear and dealer William Macbeth. Also found are scattered business records; five diaries written by Bohm's wife Zella; other notes and writings; art work including sketchbooks, loose drawings, and oil paintings; printed material; and photographs of Bohm, his family, and colleagues including artists attending a Salmagundi dinner. There is also a motion picture film Six Foot Art, in Which Max Bohm, Member of the National Academy Tells How He Does It.
Family correspondence consists of letters exchanged between various Bohm family members during their long periods of separation. Decades of almost daily exchanges of letters offer detailed descriptions of Bohm's activities in pursuit of notoriety as an artist including his frequent travels in Europe and the United States, attendance of art-related and other cultural events, and his thoughts about art, philosophy, and his strong opposition to German aggression in World War I. The often affectionate letters from Bohm's wife Zella describe her concerns over finances and raising the children during Bohm's frequent absences, but also include descriptions of their summers in coastal France.
General correspondence consists of scattered letters discussing art-related business with colleagues including Bohm's longtime patron and Christian Science advocate, Mary Bucher Longyear, and Macbeth Gallery owners Robert and William Macbeth. Scattered business records include price lists for art work, banking records, and miscellaneous receipts.
Five diaries and loose diary pages written by Bohm's wife Zella contain detailed descriptions of daily activities and her observations and thoughts, some drawings, notes, and financial notations. Some of the diaries contain annotations by her daughter, Esther.
Notes and writings include notebooks containing original short stories and miscellaneous sketches by Bohm, lists of art work, miscellaneous notes including several written by Esther Bohm, and miscellaneous writings by and about Bohm including his typescript "An Artist's Philosophy."
Art work consists of fifteen sketchbooks, miscellaneous drawings including a self-portrait, and oil paintings on board and on unstretched canvases including Bohm's studies of works by Titian and Van Dyke, and a painting of a young Esther Bohm looking at the sea. Works by others include a batik design on silk by Zella Bohm, a watercolor by Bohm's aunt, Anna Stuhr Weitz, and an oil portrait of Zella by her granddaughter.
Printed material primarily consists of clippings generated by Bohm's participation in the Paris Salons, in addition to several exhibition announcements and catalogs for Bohm and for others, and reproductions of art work by Bohm and others.
Photographs are of Bohm and his family, colleagues including Clyde du Vernet Hunt in his studio and a Salmagundi Club "Get Together" dinner, views of the town of Etaples, France, and of works of art by Bohm and others.
The silent, black and white 16mm motion picture film Six Foot Art, in Which Max Bohm, Member of the National Academy Tells How He Does It shows Max Bohm describing his method of preparing mentally and physically to create a painting. There is also a 35mm (negative) copy of this film.
Arrangement
The papers have been organized into 9 series. Each series is arranged chronologically.
Series 1: Biographical Material, 1898-1970 (Box 1, OV 8; 7 folders)
Series 2: Correspondence, 1880-1955 (Boxes 1-4, 7; 3.3 linear feet)
Series 3: Business Records, 1910-1933 (Box 4; 13 folders)
Series 4: Diaries, 1887-1916 (Box 1; 8 folders)
Series 5: Notes and Writings, 1882-1945 (Boxes 4, 7; 11 folders)
Series 6: Art Work, 1873-1951 (Boxes 4-5, 7, OVs 9-10; 31 folders)
Series 7: Printed Material, 1886-1957 (Boxes 5-6; 30 folders)
Series 8: Photographs, 1886-1959 (Boxes 6-7; 7 folders)
Series 9: Motion Picture Film, 1923 (Box 6; 1 folder)
Names and Subject Terms
This collection is indexed in the online catalog of the Archives of American Art under the following terms:
Subjects:
Beachcombers --Organization; Salmagundi Club
Subjects-Topical:
Art -- Philosophy; Painting, American -- Massachusetts -- Provincetown; Painters --Massachusetts -- Provincetown
Types of Materials:
Diaries; Motion pictures -- visual works; Paintings; Photographs; Sketchbooks; Sketches; Writings
Names:
Macbeth, William, 1851-1917; Locke, Esther Bohm, d. 1913; Bohm, Zella Newcomb
Series Descriptions/Container Listing
- Biographical Material, 1898-1970, Series 1:; (Box 1, OV 8; 7 folders)
  Biographical material consists of calling cards for Max Bohm, biographical accounts, and award certificates from the Société des Artistes Français Salon of 1898, Exposition Universelle de Médaille d'Argent, the Pan-American Exposition in Buffalo, the Universal Exposition of St. Louis, and the Panama-Pacific International Exposition. A file concerning the art club/association The Beachcombers contains the organization's constitution and by-laws, an etching of a party invitation, a booklet of their history, notes and writings, clippings, miscellaneous printed material, and photographs of members participating in costumed events.
  - Calling Cards, Biographical Accounts and Award Certificates, 1898-1915, undated, (Oversized material housed in OV 8) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - File Concerning The Beachcombers, 1917-1970, undated, (4 folders) (Box 1, Folder 2-5)
  - Oversized, Five Award Certificates, 1898-1915, undated, (From Box 1, folder 1) (Box OV 8)
- Correspondence, 1880-1955, Series 2:; (Boxes 1-4, 7; 3.3 linear feet)
  Family correspondence consists of letters exchanged between various Bohm family members during their long periods of separation. The letters describe Bohm's activities in the studio, his wife's worries about finances and raising the children, and the family's increasing interest in Christian Science. Zella's expressed worries about finances are interspersed with descriptions of the children's idyllic summer days living primarily in French coastal towns, and the family's increasing interest in Christian Science. Several letters have annotations written by Bohm's daughter Esther. Approximately one fourth of the Family Correspondence is written in German, with a few letters in French. General Correspondence consists of letters discussing art-related business with patron and friend Mary Bucher Longyear, and art dealers Robert and William Macbeth, among others.
  - Family Correspondence, undated, (oversized materials housed in Box 7) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Family Correspondence, 1880-1882 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Family Correspondence, 1883 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Family Correspondence, 1884, (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 9-10)
  - Family Correspondence, 1885 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Family Correspondence, 1886 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Family Correspondence, 1887, (8 folders) (Box 1, Folder 13-20)
  - Family Correspondence, 1888, (7 folders) (Box 1, Folder 21-27)
  - Family Correspondence, 1889, (6 folders) (Box 1, Folder 28-33)
  - Family Correspondence, 1890, (6 folders) (Box 1, Folder 34-39)
  - Family Correspondence, 1891, (4 folders) (Box 1, Folder 40-43)
  - Family Correspondence, 1892-1893 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Family Correspondence, 1894, (6 folders) (Box 1, Folder 45-50)
  - Family Correspondence, 1895, (6 folders) (Box 1, Folder 51-56)
  - Family Correspondence, 1896, (3 folders; oversized material housed in Box 7) (Box 1, Folder 57-59)
  - Family Correspondence, 1897, (4 folders; oversized material housed in Box 7) (Box 1, Folder 60-63)
  - Family Correspondence, 1898, (7 folders) (Box 1, Folder 64-70)
  - Family Correspondence, 1899, (10 folders; oversized material housed in Box 7) (Box 1, Folder 71-80)
  - Family Correspondence, 1900, (5 folders) (Box 1, Folder 81-85)
  - Family Correspondence, 1901, (6 folders) (Box 1, Folder 86-91)
  - Family Correspondence, 1902, (5 folders) (Box 1, Folder 92-96)
  - Family Correspondence, 1903, (4 folders) (Box 1, Folder 97-100)
  - Family Correspondence, 1904, (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
  - Family Correspondence, 1905, (4 folders) (Box 2, Folder 3-6)
  - Family Correspondence, 1906 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Family Correspondence, 1907, (7 folders) (Box 2, Folder 8-14)
  - Family Correspondence, 1908, (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 15-16)
  - Family Correspondence, 1909, (11 folders) (Box 2, Folder 17-27)
  - Family Correspondence, 1910, (9 folders) (Box 2, Folder 28-36)
  - Family Correspondence, 1911, (7 folders) (Box 2, Folder 37-43)
  - Family Correspondence, 1912, (12 folders) (Box 2, Folder 44-55)
  - Family Correspondence, 1913, (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 56-57)
  - Family Correspondence, 1914, (13 folders) (Box 2, Folder 58-70)
  - Family Correspondence, 1915, (13 folders) (Box 2, Folder 71-83)
  - Family Correspondence, 1916, (6 folders) (Box 2, Folder 84-89)
  - Family Correspondence, 1916, (12 folders) (Box 3, Folder 1-12)
  - Family Correspondence, 1917, (8 folders) (Box 3, Folder 13-20)
  - Family Correspondence, 1918, (13 folders) (Box 3, Folder 21-33)
  - Family Correspondence, 1919, (26 folders) (Box 3, Folder 34-59)
  - Family Correspondence, 1920, (6 folders) (Box 3, Folder 60-65)
  - Family Correspondence, 1921, (12 folders) (Box 3, Folder 66-77)
  - Family Correspondence, 1922, (4 folders) (Box 4, Folder 1-4)
  - Family Correspondence, 1923, (7 folders) (Box 4, Folder 5-11)
  - Family Correspondence, 1924-1955 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - General Correspondence, undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - General Correspondence, 1895-1909 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - General Correspondence, 1910, (Oversized material housed in Box 7) (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - General Correspondence, 1911-1912 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - General Correspondence, 1913 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - General Correspondence, 1914, (2 folders) (Box 4, Folder 18-19)
  - General Correspondence, 1915 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - General Correspondence, 1916-1919 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - General Correspondence, 1920, (2 folders) (Box 4, Folder 22-23)
  - General Correspondence, 1921 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - General Correspondence, 1923, (2 folders) (Box 4, Folder 25-26)
  - General Correspondence, 1924-1929 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - General Correspondence, 1930, (2 folders) (Box 4, Folder 28-29)
  - General Correspondence, 1931 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Seven Oversized Letters, 1896-1899, undated, (from Box 1; folders 57-63, 71-80) (Box 7 (sol))
  - Two Oversized Letters, 1910, (from Box 4, folder 14) (Box 7 (sol))
- Business Records, 1910-1933, Series 3:; (Box 4; 13 folders)
  Scattered business records include a statement by Max Bohm granting short-term power of attorney to his brother Gustave, price lists concerning real estate, price lists for art work, and miscellaneous tax and banking records, and receipts.
  - Power of Attorney, 1922 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Taxes, 1922 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Real Estate Price Lists, undated (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Price Lists for Art Work, 1924-1930, undated, (2 folders) (Box 4, Folder 34-35)
  - Check Registers, 1921-1926, (2 folders) (Box 4, Folder 36-37)
  - Cancelled Checks, 1915-1933, (4 folders) (Box 4, Folder 38-41)
  - Miscellaneous Receipts, 1910-1930, undated, (2 folders) (Box 4, Folder 42-43)
- Diaries, 1887-1916, Series 4:; (Box 1; 8 folders)
  Five diaries and loose diary entries were written by Zella Bohm and contain detailed descriptions of activities and thoughts, some drawings, notes, and financial notations, as well as annotations by her daughter, Esther. One diary was transcribed prior to donation.
  - Loose Diary Pages, undated (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Diary, 1887 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Diary, 1897 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Diary, 1898 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Typescript of Diary, 1905 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Loose Diary Pages, 1905 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Diary, 1905-1915 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Diary, 1916 (Box 4, Folder 51)
- Notes and Writings, 1882-1945, Series 5:; (Boxes 4, 7; 11 folders)
  Notes and writings include notebooks containing original short stories and miscellaneous sketches by Bohm, lists of art work, miscellaneous notes including several written by Bohm's daughter Esther, and miscellaneous writings by and about Bohm. Also included is a souvenir map of an Atlantic voyage annotated with the location of the Titanic's sinking.
  - Notebook 1, 1882 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Notebook 2, 1884 (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Lists of Art Work, 1930, undated (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, 1912, undated, (2 folders; oversized materials housed in box 7) (Box 4, Folder 55-56)
  - Illustrated Manuscript "A Trip to Mt. Marcy" by Max Bohm, undated (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Typescript, "An Artist's Philosophy" by Max Bohm, undated (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - Typescript, "A Souvenir of Max Bohm" by Louis K. Anspacher, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - Miscellaneous Writings by Bohm Family Members, 1909, undated (Box 4, Folder 60)
  - Miscellaneous Writings about Max Bohm by Others, undated (Box 4, Folder 61)
  - Oversized Route Map of S. S. Rochambeau Voyage with Annotation about the Titanic, 1912, (from box 4, folders 55-56) (Box 7 (sol))
- Artwork, 1873-1951, Series 6:; (Boxes 4-5, 7, OVs 9-10; 31 folders)
  Art work consists of fifteen sketchbooks, drawings including a self-portrait, oil paintings on board and on unstretched canvases, and works by others including a batik design on silk by Zella Bohm, a watercolor by Bohm's aunt, Anna Stuhr Weitz, and an oil portrait of Zella by her granddaughter.
  - Sketchbook 1, undated (Box 4, Folder 62)
  - Sketchbook 2, undated (Box 4, Folder 63)
  - Sketchbook 3, undated (Box 4, Folder 64)
  - Sketchbooks 4-5, undated, (oversized; housed in Box 7) (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - Sketchbook 6, undated (Box 4, Folder 66)
  - Sketchbook 7, 1873 (Box 4, Folder 67)
  - Sketchbook 8, 1874 (Box 4, Folder 68)
  - Sketchbook 9, 1876 (Box 4, Folder 69)
  - Sketchbook 10, 1884 (Box 4, Folder 70)
  - Sketchbook 11, 1884 (Box 4, Folder 71)
  - Sketchbook 12, 1889 (Box 4, Folder 72)
  - Sketchbook 13, 1910 (Box 4, Folder 73)
  - Sketchbook 14, 1912 (Box 4, Folder 74)
  - Sketchbook 15, 1914, (oversized material housed in Box 7) (Box 4, Folder 75)
  - Drawings, 1874-1914, undated, (7 folders; oversized materials housed in Box 7) (Box 5 (hol), Folder 1-7)
  - Drawings by Others, 1879-1916 (Box 5 (hol), Folder 8)
  - Paintings, 1909, undated, (2 folders; oversized materials housed in Box 7, OVs 9-10) (Box 5 (hol), Folder 9-10)
  - Painting and Batik Design on Silk by Zella Bohm, undated, (Oversized materials housed in OV 8) (Box 5 (hol), Folder 11)
  - Watercolor by Anna Stuhr Weitz, 1896 (Box 5 (hol), Folder 12)
  - Painting of Zella Bohm by Anne Locke, 1951 (Box 5 (hol), Folder 13)
  - Oversized Sketchbooks 4, 5, and 15, 1914, undated, (also referenced in Box 4, folders 64-65, 76) (Box 7 (sol))
  - Fourteen Oversized Drawings, 1880-1914, undated, (from Box 5, folders 1-7) (Box 7 (sol))
  - Three Oversized Paintings on Unstretched Canvases, undated, (from Box 5, folders 9-10) (Box 7 (sol))
  - Oversized Batik Design on Silk by Zella Bohm, undated, (from Box 5, folder 11) (Box OV 8)
  - Three Oversized Oil Paintings on Unstretched Canvases, undated, (from Box 5, folders 9-10) (Box OV 9)
  - Three Oversized Oil Paintings on Unstretched Canvases, undated, (from Box 5, folders 9-10) (Box OV 10)
- Printed Material, 1886-1957, Series 7:; (Boxes 5-6; 30 folders)
  Printed material includes clippings, exhibition announcements and catalogs for Bohm and for others, and reproductions of art work by Bohm and others.
  - Clippings, undated, (2 folders) (Box 5 (hol), Folder 14-15)
  - Clippings, 1888-1896, (Oversized also in Box 7) (Box 5 (hol), Folder 16)
  - Clippings, 1897, (Oversized also in Box 7) (Box 5 (hol), Folder 17)
  - Clippings, 1898-1899 (Box 5 (hol), Folder 18)
  - Clippings, 1900-1909, (Oversized also in Box 7) (Box 5 (hol), Folder 19)
  - Clippings, 1910, (Oversized also in Box 7) (Box 5 (hol), Folder 20)
  - Clippings, 1911 (Box 5 (hol), Folder 21)
  - Clippings, 1912, (2 folders; oversized also in Box 7) (Box 5 (hol), Folder 22-23)
  - Clippings, 1913 (Box 5 (hol), Folder 24)
  - Clippings, 1914 (Box 5 (hol), Folder 25)
  - Clippings, 1915 (Box 5 (hol), Folder 26)
  - Clippings, 1916, (3 folders) (Box 5 (hol), Folder 27-29)
  - Clippings, 1917, (Oversized also in Box 7) (Box 5 (hol), Folder 30)
  - Clippings, 1918-1922, (Oversized also in Box 7) (Box 6 (hol), Folder 1)
  - Clippings, 1923 (Box 6 (hol), Folder 2)
  - Clippings, 1924 (Box 6 (hol), Folder 3)
  - Clippings, 1925, (Oversized also in Box 7) (Box 6 (hol), Folder 4)
  - Clippings, 1926 (Box 6 (hol), Folder 5)
  - Clippings, 1927 (Box 6 (hol), Folder 6)
  - Clippings, 1928-1957 (Box 6 (hol), Folder 7)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, 1916-1932, undated (Box 6 (hol), Folder 8)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs for Others, 1886, undated, (2 folders) (Box 6 (hol), Folder 9-10)
  - Reproductions of Art Work for YMCA Publications, undated (Box 6 (hol), Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous Reproductions of Art Work by Others, undated (Box 6 (hol), Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Material, 1891, undated (Box 6 (hol), Folder 13)
  - Oversized Clippings, 1891-1925, (from Box 5, folders 16-17, 19, 20, 22-23, 30; Box 6, folders 1, 4) (Box 7 (hol))
- Photographs, 1886-1959, Series 8:; (Boxes 6-7; 7 folders)
  Photographs are of Bohm, his family, colleagues including Clyde du Vernet Hunt in his studio and a Salmagundi Club dinner, views of the town of Etaples, France, where Bohm spent his early career, and of works of art by Bohm and others.
  - Photographs of Max Bohm, 1886-1899 (Box 6 (hol), Folder 14)
  - Photographs of the Bohm Family and Colleagues, 1922, undated, (Oversized also in Box 7) (Box 6 (hol), Folder 15)
  - Photographs of Etaples, France, undated (Box 6 (hol), Folder 16)
  - Photographs of Esther Bohm Locke in Pont-Aven, France, 1959 (Box 6 (hol), Folder 17)
  - Photographs of Art Work, undated, (Oversized also in Box 7) (Box 6 (hol), Folder 18)
  - Photographs of Art Work by Clyde duVernet Hunt, 1897 (Box 6 (hol), Folder 19)
  - Two Oversized Photograph of Bohm's Grandparents and Other Family Members; Oversized Photograph of Clyde du Vernet Hunt in His Studio; Two Oversized Photographs of a Salmagundi Club Dinner; An Oversized Photograph of Art Work, 1922, undated, (from Box 6, folders 15, 18) (Box 7 (sol))
- Motion Picture Film, Series 9:; (Box 6; 1 folder)